Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Now passing through Geschtam Gate.
Estimated arrival at Balun is tam 07:30.
Linking to system satellites.
We were fortunate that Domel brought the UX01.
If the hound's net snares its prey, we'll do it at the Aquarius Ruins.
Will that be acceptable, Mirenel?
Zar Balk.
Launch in:
Launch!
That's the last one. They're all deployed!
What are those things?
I don't know.
You don't know? I thought we were getting supplies.
Instead, they have us distributing these weird things.
We aren't cargo haulers. We're warriors.
Seriously!
Don't get so upset.
Our next mission comes directly from Lord Desler.
Then what of the Yamato? We're leaving Domel's command?
Yeah... The vixen will handle the Yamato personally.
Nothing on hyperspace sonar.
Not even a ripple at the dimensional boundary line.
Looks like that ship isn't lying in wait along the Yamato's course.
Yeah.
The Milky Way, huh?
Yeah, our Earth is somewhere within that flood of light.
And our destination, Iscandar, lies in the Large Magellanic Cloud.
We still have a long way.
Hey, Kodai...
What?
This is a good chance.
Want to let me pilot for a bit?
Nope.
Our patrol's over, so why not?
We don't have so many of these. We can afford to lose one.
What's that supposed to mean?
Just what I said.
Lt. Kodai, as Operations Officer,
I order you to transfer control to me.
It's nice to be young.
As Tactical Officer, I refuse.
Your authority as Tactical Officer is suspended due to what happened.
You're bringing that up?
What is this?
I am.
003, this is the Yamato.
Sorry to interrupt, but we can hear everything you say.
XO, why did you pick those two?
Lt. Mort's expertise makes her ideal
to test the prototype hyperspace sonar.
And with his normal authority rescinded, Lt. Kodai has nothing better to do.
It's quite logical.
Oh...
Snow?
What?
What is this?
A song? Someone's sing—
What's wrong, Aihara? Come in, Yamato!
Yamato!
Mori?
Returning to base.
Hey, look at that.
What's going on?
I can't access the hangar.
I'm retaking control.
SID, maintain synchronization with the ship.
Roger.
What should we do?
We'll use the emergency airlock.
Where did everyone go?
Analyzer...?
The momentum control system still appears to be on line.
Course correction confirmed.
No good... I can't access it.
Where are we going?
Autopilot
Cancellation Failure
But if the ship's moving, that means the nav system is working.
The only places we can access it are the central computer room...
...and the automatic navigation room.
This isn't right...
Something is happening on this ship.
But what could it be?
Main Elevator
Emergency
Shut Down
That's strange.
The power's back, but the elevator isn't working.
And the emergency stairs are locked, so we can't reach them.
Understood.
Kodai? Kodai?
Are you all right?
Sorry, it was nothing.
Sorry...
Ah, no problem.
The central computer room and automatic navigation.
Should we split up?
No, it's too risky in this situation.
Got it.
Zero.
Mori...
Mori?
Hello?
Susumu, where are you?
Everyone was worried. Get back here.
Mom?
To the person in my memory.
Think it's Mamoru?
He's back on Earth, right? I'm sure it is.
The whole Kodai family is here today.
Dad, Mom... And my uncles, too?
That's impossible. They all died that day.
It's been a long time, Susumu.
What's wrong? Aren't you going to answer the phone?
Hello?
Is that you, Susumu?
Mamoru...?
I'll be there in twenty.
Sorry I'm late.
Why did you die, Mamoru?
What about you?
Are you still alive?
What are you doing?
I'm on the Yamato.
That isn't where you belong. Come back, Susumu.
You weren't the kind of person who should be fighting.
Your big brother is right.
Let's go back home together, Susumu.
No, I have to get back.
Get back? To where?
To the Yamato.
The Yamato? Why?
To fight.
To fight? Against whom?
Against whom? Who else?
Let's see...
Who was it I was fighting?
This is the Earth.
Uncle Hijikata?
In the twentieth century,
it was normal for families to gather around tables like this for meals.
Kodai?
Here, you will learn about Earth, and you will live as an Earthling.
Let me introduce your partner. This is she.
Hello. Nice to meet you.
Are you awake?
Where am I?
The central hospital.
You shouldn't move yet!
What happened to me?
I can't remember.
You hit your head hard. You probably have amnesia.
...Yuki Mori, caught in the explosion, was taken to the hospital,
where she is still in a coma.
Midnight Highway Explosion — Terrorism?
Police are also investigating the possibility of terrorism.
An air raid warning has been issued!
An air raid warning—
Mamoru?
Susumu, you're a man. Stop crying.
Dad gave me this a long time ago.
I want you to have it.
You take this...
No way... This can't be...
What are you doing here?
It's okay, Yuki.
Yuki
Snow
Yuki?
Misaki?
Misaki? Who's that?
This ship is moving. It has a Wave Motion Engine.
What are you talking about? Where is everyone?
I woke up and found myself here.
I see.
This is...
Planet bombs.
Susumu, don't forget this sight.
No good, the course information is locked here, too.
Where are we warping?
They're waiting for you there. They're waiting for this ship.
This ship has a Wave Motion Engine.
So if you remove the Wave Motion Core, it will stop.
You stay here.
Wave Motion Engine...
Preparing to Warp
Oh. My sister is here.
120 seconds until warp.
30 seconds until warp.
Mom... Jiro...
Countdown to warp: 10, 9, 8...
You don't hold back, do you?
7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2...
Operations Officer Mori's access authorized.
Disconnect of Wave Motion Core
system's primary connection initiated.
Multidimensional momentum-conservation of quantum flywheel complete.
Power capacitors fully charged.
Power bus connections severed at all phases.
Initiating Standby
Deploying Wave Motion Shield in core conduit bay.
Wave Motion Shield deployment confirmed.
Wave Motion Core may be safely removed.
Connected
Severed
Yuki, what are you doing?
Now, put that back.
But this is...
That's an order. Put it back.
But...
If you don't, Earth will be destroyed.
Destroyed? The Earth?
Yes...
Your home, which you love so much.
My home...
Yes, your home.
Now... Bring it here.
Emergency Exit
Occupied
Mamoru's late.
Maybe his ship's delayed.
I wasn't here that day.
I went to the space port to pick up my brother, but then...
Look! What's that?
It fell on my city.
Don't be stupid.
Earth is at peace.
There is no war.
There is a war...
The enemy is Garmillas. And a planet bomb landed here...
And everyone died!
That's right.
Good girl... Just put it back.
Mori...
Save
Me
Yuki!
Activating
That hurt.
A Geschtam Field!
Releasing Wave Motion Field in conduit bay.
Please evacuate immediately.
Restarting Wave Motion Engine.
Ghost Link severed. Special Operations Officer Linke's mind isn't returning to her body.
Transferred data has been saved.
Now I'm all alone...
Those ruins were left by the race that built the gates.
There's a rumor that she is one of their descendants.
What did she come here to accomplish, anyway?
I doubt any normal man could understand a witch's motives.
Who are you calling normal?
Both that annoying wolf and the vixen are now fixated on the Yamato?
Yes.
Then it's time...
What are you talking about?
You have no need to know.
Doctor Sado says everyone saw
whatever memory they most cherish.
I saw my mom and dad.
And...
What did you see?
Oh... Sorry.
I...
I saw someone I cared about, as well.
In the end, you came for me, didn't you Kodai?
U-Um...
W-Wait, Mori...
What does that mean?
It's a secret.
Farewell, me.
Hello, you.
You are Misaki.
Yuria Misaki.
Episode 14
The Whisper of the Witch
Believe that
Only the future
Has the answer
No one knows
Memory only strikes at
The heart to find
The truth
Do not forget it…
Many stars lie beyond
The spiral of memory
Sparkling in what looks like
The light of memory
In the vast space between galaxies,
a trap is laid by a patient enemy.
The Yamato is surrounded.
With hell ahead of them and hell behind,
there's no turning back.
Yamato, escape this deadly trap!
Next time: Point of No Return.
There are 298 days left before humanity is extinct.